( dramatic music ) ( projector whirring )
( ominous music )
( water running )
( beeping )
- [ Mike ] Kay , hi , it 's Mike Adler here from Creswick Police .
Look , I 'm just calling about your mum .
The neighbors haven 't seen her in a few days .
I 've been by her house without much luck
and I was just wondering if you 'd heard from her .
Could you give me a call when you can ?
Thanks .
( knocking on door )
- Gran ?
Gran ?
( knocking on door )
( ominous music )
- [ Kay ] Mum ?
- Gran ?
- [ Kay ] Wait .
Just wait out here .
Mum ?
You should set up in my old room .
- [ Sam ] What ?
Kay , what ? - Nothing .
Call straightaway if she ... - Yeah , I will .
- Okay .
- [ Mike ] Does your mum still drive ?
- [ Kay ] Sometimes but her car 's still at the house .
- [ Mike ] And any medical problems ?
- [ Kay ] No .
She 's in her 80s , she forgets things .
She managed to flood the house last Christmas .
- [ Mike ] And when was the last time you spoke to her ?
- It 's been a while .
- [ Mike ] Could you be more specific ?
- Um .
- [ Mike ] Well , in situations like this ,
we need to come up with a time line .
When Alex called last night , he
said he hadn 't noticed your mum leave the house for a few
days , maybe a week , so , if we can figure out who the last
person was to speak to her , we can ...
- Yeah , of course , yeah . - Figure out exactly who .
- Sorry .
It 's been a few weeks .
Work 's been crazy , you know how it is .
- [ Mike ] And what did you talk about ?
- Nothing , really , normal stuff .
- [ Mike ] She didn 't mention anything about a holiday ,
appointment out of town , visiting friends ?
- No .
Nothing like that .
- We 'll organize the overall search strategy .
- Okay .
- Did you bring a recent photo ?
- [ Kay ] Yeah .
This was taken late last year .
- Jesus Christ .
Great .
( door creaking )
( ominous music )
- She 's been putting food out for Chester .
Is your boss okay with you taking time off ?
- Yeah .
Well , no .
I stopped working at the gallery .
- Since when ?
- A while .
- What are you doing for money ?
- I got some decent shifts back at the bar .
- Still planning on going back to uni ?
- [ Sam ] I don 't know , Kay .
- So , what , you 're just gonna work in a bar
for the rest of your life ?
- Yeah , maybe .
- I 'm glad you 're here .
I 'm not sure what I 'm supposed to be doing .
- I think you 're doing it .
- [ Mike ] Edna ?
Edna ?
- [ Kay ] Mum ?
- [ Mike ] Edna ?
Edna ?
- [ Kay ] Mum ?
- [ Woman ] Edna !
- [ Mike ] Edna !
Edna !
We 'll regroup first thing tomorrow .
- [ Sam ] We should check the trail by St. George 's Lake .
Gran used to take me there .
( vacuum running )
( ominous music )
Gran ?
Jamie ?
- [ Jamie ] Hi , Sam .
- What are you up to ?
- [ Jamie ] Patrolling .
- Okay .
- Did you find her yet ?
- No , not yet .
When was the last time you saw her ?
- Not for ages .
Dad doesn 't like me coming over anymore .
- Why 's that ?
- Smells weird .
Can I have a go ?
I 'm allowed .
- You 're 18 !
When did that happen ?
( coughing )
- Oh !
- Thanks , Jamie , I really needed that .
I might go inside , it 's freezing .
Do you want to come in ?
Make you a Milo ?
- Nah .
That 's okay .
( piano playing )
( piano music )
- It 's D after that bit , not E.
- How do you know ?
- [ Sam ] Gran taught me .
- Of course she did .
I could never get the curl of the fingers right .
I think she gave up on me at a certain point .
- Are these locks new too ?
- I think she was scared .
- Scared , of what ?
- She called me a few weeks ago , she thought someone
was coming into the house .
- What , why ?
- Doors were left open , the lights were left on , she ,
armchair had shifted .
- Well ,
did you tell the police ?
- She forgets things , you know what she 's like , it was her .
- Well , why didn 't you call me , I could have driven up here .
I mean , what if she was ?
( ominous music )
( banging noise )
What was that ?
Kay ?
- Don 't know .
( knocking )
( banging noise )
- What is that ?
( ominous music )
( door creaking )
( flies buzzing )
What 's wrong ?
- [ Kay ] Nothing .
Go to sleep .
( kettle whistling )
Mum ?
Where have you been ?
- Tea ?
- You okay ?
- [ Edna ] One sugar , right ?
- Gran ! - Oh !
- [ Kay ] About half an hour ago .
No , she 's not hurt .
As far as I can tell , she won 't tell me anything .
Whenever I ask , she just changes the subject ,
acts like nothing happened , like she
hasn 't been gone for three days .
Yeah , I don 't wanna push her , I just hope she 's okay .
Yeah , thanks , Mike , yeah , I will , bye .
- Any chest pain ?
- No .
- Breathlessness , dysuria ?
- [ Edna ] Dysuria ?
- Does it hurt to pee ?
- Oh , no , neither of those things .
- Would you mind taking a slow walk
to your daughter and back ?
Edna , when 's your birthday ?
- [ Edna ] April 10th .
- [ Nurse ] And how about your granddaughter 's ?
- [ Edna ] March 3rd .
- Good .
- See , this one worries about me .
- May I ? - Mm hm .
- Do you know how you got this bruise ?
- Oh , I must have knocked it , clumsy .
- Just to be safe , I 'm going to recommend that you not
be by yourself for the next couple of weeks .
- Is that really necessary ?
- [ Nurse ] Sorry , Edna , I insist .
- House arrest it is , then .
- Well , tell them it 's a family emergency .
Yeah , I know that , but he 's perfectly capable .
A week , maybe two .
Well , what do you expect ?
Yeah , fine , fine , email it .
I 've gotta go , Luce .
- [ Edna ] What 's that ?
- Do you know where you were , Mum ?
- [ Edna ] Where ?
- No , I 'm asking you .
- [ Edna ] I suppose I went out .
- Out where ?
- If I 'd known you 'd call the police ,
I would have stayed home .
- [ Kay ] There 's blood on your nightgown .
Do you need help ?
- With what ?
- There are Post-it notes everywhere , Mum .
- [ Edna ] It 's my house , I can decorate it however I want .
- Just tell me what happened !
- [ Sam ] Look , can we just take it easy today ?
Gran must be exhausted .
( ominous music )
( knocking on door ) Gran ?
Oh .
Got your tea .
- What service !
- Sorry about Mum .
She was worried about you .
We all were .
- [ Edna ] I had to stop wearing it .
They say you shrink with age , but my fingers
just keep getting fatter .
- It 's lovely .
- It 's yours .
- Gran , I can 't take this .
- You might need it one day .
And your mother 's already had a go .
- [ Sam ] Wow , you cleaned up .
- Please leave it , I 've got a system .
- [ Sam ] What are you doing ?
- Work .
- [ Sam ] Look at this .
- Guess I was .
Wow .
He could draw .
- Yeah .
- God , I haven 't seen this for years .
- [ Sam ] Wait , what 's this ?
- Oh , that was on the property when your
grandparents inherited it .
- My great-grandfather lived there ?
By himself ?
- Yeah , there were all these stories .
Apparently , his mind wasn 't all there in the end
and nobody knew how bad it was .
I don 't think he was cared for like he
should have been , you know ?
I was happy to see it go .
Mum used to threaten to lock me
in it when I was being a brat .
- Is that the same window as the one on the door downstairs ?
- Yeah .
Yeah , when they tore it down , they saved some of the windows
and used them to build into this place .
Can you keep an eye on her for a few hours tomorrow ?
- Where are you going ?
- [ Kay ] Back to Melbourne .
- You going back to work ?
- No , I 've booked a tour of a retirement place .
- You can 't put Gran in a home .
- You heard her before , she doesn 't know where she was .
I don 't think she can remember .
- That 's not what I heard .
- She can 't live on her own anymore , Sam .
- Well , why can 't she move in with you ?
- Because that 's not practical .
- There 's plenty of room at your place .
- No , it 's not about room , she has to be watched .
- Well , isn 't that how it works ?
Your mum changes your nappies , then you change hers ?
- You need to be on the same side as me for this .
( chuckling )
- Does Gran even get a say ?
- This is what 's best for Gran .
- [ Edna ] What noise ?
No , I didn 't hear anything .
I told you , I told you it 's nothing .
There 's no one .
You 're scaring me .
- [ Kay ] Mum ?
( ominous music )
Are you all right ?
- [ Edna ] Are you leaving ?
- No , Mum .
- [ Edna ] That 's good .
- Will you be all right now ?
Mum ?
Mum , what is it ?
- It 's here .
Under the bed .
- No , there 's nothing under the bed , Mum .
- Are you sure ?
- [ Kay ] Yes .
- Will you check for me ?
Please .
- See , nothing .
- You didn 't look .
- Ow , shit , oh !
Oh !
You did that on purpose .
- Did what ? - You dropped that on purpose !
- Why would I do that ? - I don 't know .
- Did you hit your head ? - Yes , yes , yes .
- [ Nurse ] Now , you mentioned your mother
has some cognitive impairment ?
- [ Kay ] Yeah , I don 't really know , she forgets things .
She 's started wandering .
- Well , the staff here are on call 24 / 7 .
Think of it as independent living with the edges taken off .
Just in here .
This side of the building has ocean views .
Handrails in every room , high toilet seat , mobility aids
if your mother needs help getting in and out of bed .
- No , she 's fine with that kind of stuff .
She 's fit , she 's active .
I 'm not even sure she 's ready for a place like this .
- [ Nurse ] Well , it 's five-star living .
Then there 's the lifestyle and therapy programs ,
disability support , computer classes .
Your mum 'll make friends in no time .
The rec room is decked out and every Sunday night .
♪ I would change November showers ♪
♪ To red roses in June ♪
♪ These are the things the things I 'd do for you ♪
♪ Though I 'm not a great musician ♪
- Dance with me , Kimmy .
♪ I have always had ♪
- Sorry ?
- Dance with me , Sammy .
Ah ! - Oh , no .
- Yes , here we go . - Gran .
Oh , boy .
- Do you know the cha-cha ?
- Absolutely not . - Time for a lesson .
One , two , three and one , two , three .
And one , two , three and it 's the cha-cha .
- Okay . ( chuckling )
- And under arm for the lady .
- Oh , the lady . - And again .
And one more for Sammy .
( chuckling )
♪ As late ♪
♪ As the hour ♪
This one always gets me .
♪ I beg you please ♪
- Do you ever get lonely out here by yourself ?
♪ As late ♪
♪ As the hour ♪
Jamie doesn 't come around here much anymore , does he ?
♪ Cling to me ♪
- Who ?
- Jamie from next door .
- Oh .
The retard .
♪ Is an atmosphere ♪
♪ We should share ♪
- How would you feel about me moving to Creswick ?
( chuckling )
- Why would you want to do that ?
- To be closer to you .
I could help you out , cook , clean , stuff like that .
- Was this your idea or your mother 's ?
- Mine .
- [ Edna ] Where would you live ?
- Here , in the house with you .
- [ Edna ] I don 't think so .
I 'm not a project , Kay .
- I 'm Sam , Gran .
- I know who you are .
- Well , wouldn 't it be better than moving
into an old folks ' home ?
That 's where Mum is right now ,
checking out a place in Melbourne .
Here , let me help .
- What 's this ? - What ?
- What are you doing with this ?
- What do you mean ? - This is mine .
- Yeah , Gran , you gave it to ... - You 're trying to steal
from me , you 're trying to rob me .
- No , remember when you ... - Give it back .
- Give it back ! - Ow , Gran .
Ow , ah , oh !
Fuck , take it !
Gran ?
- [ Kay ] Are these my school reports ?
You 're throwing these out ?
I didn 't even know you 'd kept them .
- [ Edna ] Well , I have to make room , don 't I ?
- Room for what , Mum ?
- This one 's moving in .
- No , she 's not .
I think you 're confused , Mum .
- I 'm not sure why you think it 's your decision .
How was Melbourne ?
( Edna whistling )
- [ Sam ] Everything alright , Gran ?
- [ Edna ] I don 't like this place .
- Is that why you installed the lock ?
- I thought this was where it got in .
- Who ?
- Whoever was coming into the house .
Since your grandfather passed , this house seems
unfamiliar , bigger , somehow .
This house is the only thing left .
All our memories .
I 'm glad you 're moving in , Sammy .
- Are you sure ?
( banging noise )
- [ Sam ] Gran ?
Gran ?
( banging noise )
( ominous music )
Kay ?
- [ Kay ] Mum ?
- [ Edna ] What 's that noise ?
I think there 's something in the house .
I need to go downstairs .
There 's someone down there .
- [ Kay ] Everything alright in there , Mum ?
Sammy ?
- [ Edna ] I 'm not being ridiculous , I can tell .
Sometimes they look at me
and I don 't think it 's really them .
They look like Kay and Sammy , but it 's not them .
They 're pretending .
You know what I think , I think they 're just
waiting for the day .
I think they 're hoping I 'll go to sleep and I won 't wake up .
Then they 'll dump me in the ground to rot .
I can see you .
- Who are you talking to ?
Gran , you 're bleeding .
- I can do it myself .
- You 've hurt yourself , just ... - [ Edna ] No !
- Gran , stop ! - Get out !
Get out of here !
Get out , get out , it 's my room , it 's my house ,
get out ! - I 'm sorry !
( ominous music )
- [ Jamie ] Hi , Sam .
- [ Sam ] Hey , Jamie , how are you ?
- I 'm okay .
- Is your dad home ?
- Dad ?
- Alex , what happened between Jamie and Gran ?
- They were playing hide-and-seek
and it was Jamie 's turn to hide .
And he hid , I guess , in a cupboard with a lock on it .
Well , she came along and locked the closet
and left him there .
I think she forgot they were playing .
He was trapped in that cupboard for hours .
When he didn 't come home ,
I went over there to check on him .
Edna said she hadn 't seen him .
But I could hear him screaming from upstairs .
He had paint under his fingernails
just from scratching the door .
So , we 've been keeping our distance a bit .
- Yeah , no , of course , I get it .
I 'm really sorry Jamie had to go through that .
- Okay .
( ominous music )
- Mum .
Mum , stop .
Stop !
Ow , Jesus !
What are you doing , Mum ?
No !
- Give it back ! - No , Mum , no !
- I 'm still your mother , Kay !
I think these might be safe out here .
Do you think that 's right ?
- [ Kay ] Safe from what , Mum ?
- I don 't know .
I knew it was a bad idea .
I hate that window .
I can 't bear to look at it every time
I go through that door .
There 's such a
coldness in the house .
This is what I 'm like now , it 's all I do .
I keep thinking ,
thinking maybe it 's just waiting for me , maybe
it 's just been waiting ' til I was weak enough .
Alone enough .
I wish I could bury it myself so it can 't get at me .
I just want to go home .
I just wish I could turn around
and go back .
I 'm losing everything , Kay .
- No , it 's all right , you 're not .
I 'm here .
I 'm here to help you , Mum .
Come home with me .
To Melbourne , will you move into my place , Mum ?
I 'm sorry .
Sorry I wasn 't here more .
Please let me help you .
Yeah ?
Yeah .
- Where 's ,
where 's my ,
where 's everyone ?
- Your photo album ?
It 's here .
It 's right here .
- Where 's everyone ?
- They 're here , they 're here , I 'm here .
It 's all right , Mum .
Mum .
I won 't leave you .
( ominous music )
I 'll get dinner started , what do you feel like ?
- Thanks , dear .
- Sam , we 're back !
- What the ?
Fuck this .
What ?
( banging on door ) Mum ?
Mum ?
- [ Woman ] You have called 042 .
- Well , her stuff 's still here .
You should try to eat something , Mum .
♪ Stay a little longer ♪
Mum ?
♪ As the hour ♪
♪ Cling to me ♪
♪ Make our love stronger ♪
( ominous music )
♪ I beg you please ♪
♪ Stay a little longer ♪
Oh , Jesus , Mum .
Mum , come on .
( water running )
( ominous music )
( heavy breathing )
( sobbing )
( creaking )
Mum ?
( knocking ) Mum ?
( heavy breathing )
( sobbing )
Mum !
( gasping )
Oh , Jesus , Mum !
Mum , what are you doing , Mum , stop it !
Mum , open !
Mum , Mum !
Open the door right now , Mum , oh !
Your chest , Mum .
Mum ?
Mum , Mum , stop it .
Mum !
( chair smashing )
Mum ?
Oh , shit .
What ?
( knocking )
( sobbing )
- What the fuck ?
( heavy breathing )
- [ Kay ] Oh , what ?
Mum ?
Mum , please , can we go back now ?
Ah !
Oh !
- You 're not Kay .
- Oh !
- I don 't know you .
- No , Mum , no !
( sobbing )
( grunting )
( ominous music )
( yelling )
- Mum ?
Mum ?
- [ Kay ] No !
- Mum ?
Mum ? - Where are you ?
- I 'm down here ! - Where ?
- [ Sam ] Here !
- [ Kay ] Sam , Sam ! - What happened ?
- [ Kay ] Oh , Sam , Mum is not , it 's not her anymore .
( Edna groaning )
- Mum . - Yeah .
Here , give it to me , give it to me .
Hold that , hold it !
( grunting )
- Mum ?
Is that you , Gran ?
- It 's okay , Sam , it 's okay .
( sobbing )
- Mum !
- Go , Sam , go , get in there , go !
Go , go !
Get out of here !
- I got you , I got you . - Pull me , pull me !
( yelling )
Pull me , goddamn it .
- [ Sam ] I 've got you ! I 've got you !
( yelling )
- Get me out of here !
Pull me !
( yelling )
- No ! - Mum !
Mum !
Come on , Kay .
- [ Edna ] Kay .
- Mum ?
Come on .
Mum , what is it ?
- I can 't leave her .
- What ?
No ! ( banging on door )
Please don 't , it 's not Gran anymore !
It 's not Gran !
Mum !
Please come back !
Mum , what are you doing ?
Mum , Mum , please , let 's just go !
Mum !
( ominous music )
( shushing )